- [Sam] Automation is the major driver
of our modern economy, because it allows individuals
to be more productive than ever while using fewer resources.
And as technology continues to reshape modern business,
more and more tasks can now be automated,
and automating processes doesn't have to be hard,
if you're using the right tools,
and this where Python comes in.
Python is an easy to learn programming language
that you can use to build automations.
And because Python
is the fastest growing programming language,
new tools are being developed and added every day.
My name is Sam Pettus, and I use programming languages
like Python to help businesses and individuals
solve problems and save time.
In this course, I'll introduce you
to some of the interesting ways
Python can automate computer operations.
We'll take a look at how to click and type on websites,
interact with APIs, web script datasets,
and automate file and terminal interactions and more.
By the end of this course you'll understand
the many ways Python can automate tasks,
and feel confident constructing these automations yourself.
So, if you're excited about compiling your own army
of automated robots, let's go ahead and get started.