- [Narrator] So I'm all set up on reading files,
now it's time to check out how to write files.
To demonstrate the flexibility of file writing,
let's incorporate it into our existing code.
Instead of printing the information to terminal,
let's instead write it to a new file.
Using the same open function we use to read files,
let's now use it to write files.
This line will create a new file, called PassFile.txt.
Also notice how I'm using "w" as our second parameter,
because we want to write to this file.
Finally, let's change the print statement
to a write function to update our newly created file.
Remember to close the file when you're done.
At this point, our code should produce a file
called Passfile.txt that stores all the P's.
With our code executed, let's go ahead an navigate
to our current working directory.
Great, our PassFile.txt now exists.
Let's go ahead and open it and check
if it only contains passes.
Nice, our code is working as expected.
Adding on, let's go ahead and create another file
to store the fails.
All we need to do is duplicate the previous steps.
First, let's create the file.
Then, adding some new logic, I'll write to it.
And the last step, let's make sure we close our file.
At this point, our code should create two files.
One that tracks people who passed,
and one that contains people who failed.
Let's go ahead and check if this is the case.
Now, if I again navigate back
to my current working directory, we can see now,
both the pass and the fail file exist.
Let's go ahead and check out the fail file.
As expected this file only contains the F tags,
so it looks like our program worked correctly,
and with that, you've learned the basic of file IO.