- [Instructor] I'm here on a website called,
"Quotes to Scrape" and let's say we want
to compile all the quotes,
their authors, and the tags associated
with each quote from this page.
Let's start by taking a look
at how the website is structured.
I'm going to open up the Chrome Inspector tool,
and this displays an HTML document
that creates the webpage.
To do this, go ahead and right click,
and click Inspect.
All websites have this component,
which makes our job of scraping specific data
a lot easier.
This HTML document holds every piece of information
that is visible on our page.
Meaning our quotes are hidden somewhere
in this jumble of HTML, we just got to find 'em.
So in order to get this information
to our python script, we'll need to create a get query.
So to do that, I'll first copy the website's address
and save it as a variable.
Next, let's import the libraries that we'll be using.
The request library houses the get function,
and which we'll be using to ping the web address.
This process returns a response containing the source code
from the website.
I like to think of this step
as creating connection with the URL,
and as a response, getting back a copy
of the website's HTML document.
So let's go ahead and actually create the request.
So with that done, the next piece of the puzzle is
to parse the HTML document, and for this we'll use
BeautifulSoup and lxml.
These programs work in unity
to create a navigable object
that we can use to isolate specific data
we actually want from the website.
In this line, we'll be parsing responses text attribute
and letting BeautifulSoup know we want
to use the lxml parser.
Let's go ahead and print soup to verify our connection
and see if our parser worked correctly.
And as you can see, we now have a copy
of "Quotes to Scrapes" HTML,
and we can now begin isolating specific data.