So why automate web browsing?
Well, there's really just two main purposes.
The first and more prominent reason,
is to test website functionality,
Automating testing decreases the cost and time,
while also providing a means of round the clock testing.
Additionally, it makes cross-browser proofing easier.
The second and less discussed application,
is Botting Processes online.
Botting is defined as a piece of software
that executes commands or performs routine tasks
without the users intervention.
And this can be applied to any repetitive task online.
For example, let's say you order take-out
everyday from a website.
Well, instead of manually filling out the form each time,
you can instead script the entire process.
Or perhaps, logging into a certain website
or email, becomes a tedious task.
Just script it.
Any repetitive online task can now be optimized
by creating a Python script.
However, these examples just represent benevolent
botting tasks.
Conversely, this tool can be used for much more
nefarious purposes.
One of the biggest issues
is Botting Limited Quantity Items.
Tickets to shows or exclusive merchandise
are good examples.
Normally the check out process appears fair.
As everyone must go through similar steps
before a product sells out.
But automation creates an unfair arena.
Scripts can navigate websites significantly faster
than humans, and moreover, scripts can execute
hundreds, if not thousands of requests at once.
Nearly guaranteeing the process.
Consequently, this makes botting notorious
for only being used for exploits.
But as discussed before, there are positive purposes.
All right, with that disclaimer out of the way,
let's get you set up.
We'll be using the Selenium Library to help
us interact with the web.
Go ahead and install it.
Additionally, Selenium interfaces with the internet
by using a web driver, which is a browser
that Selenium can use to automate web processes.
The two ones I recommend using are Chrome driver,
which runs Google Chrome. Or gecko driver,
which runs Firefox.
So, select whichever browser you feel more comfortable
with, and use a package installer to download
either one of the drivers.
You don't need both.
I'll be using Chrome driver and downloading it
with the Home Brew package installer.
With that setup, we're ready to begin coding.