- [Instructor] Let's check out the first step
of using APIs, creating the request.
To practice, we'll be using this free API
on upcitemdb.com.
This software translates barcodes
into a whole host of information,
including the product's name and brand.
To see an example of what an API call should look like,
let's go ahead and use their online GUI I've pulled up here.
To demo, I'll just use a LaCroix can barcode.
This is a lot of information to break down.
But for now,
let's just focus at the request URL line at the top.
This line contains two factors,
the base URL, or everything preceding the question mark,
and the parameters of the API call,
or everything after the question mark.
The base URL is independent of our parameters
and will be the same for any barcode we'll look up.
However, on the other hand,
the parameters are specific to this barcode search.
This may sounds complex
but this breaks down very simply into code.
Let me show you.
Let's start by constructing the base URL for our API call.
Just go ahead and copy the URL preceding the question mark.
Now I'll need to construct the parameters for the API call.
This is done by making a Python dictionary.
To structure this dictionary,
let's take a look
at the information after the question mark.
From the highlighted text,
you can see UPC is equal to our LaCroix barcode.
So in our dictionary,
UPC should be the key and the barcode our value.
With the bases covered,
it's time to actually invoke the API call.
To do this,
I'll use the request library
which allows us to send our GET query
containing the parameters and our base URL.
To make sure our API request was properly constructed,
let's go ahead and print out its responses URL attribute.
Comparing to the demos,
you can see we've made an exact match.
And, with that,
you've constructed your first request to an API.